Female employees consistently pay lower airfares than men do for the same flights because they tend to book earlier.
在同一航班上，女性员工支付的机票价格始终低于男性，因为她们往往订票更早。
We compared the airfare paid by employees in the same position within a company for the same class of travel and used a common statistical technique to account for other factors that might affect differences in airfares.
我们比较了同一公司内职位相同的员工乘坐同一等级舱位时所付的机票价格，并采用一种常用的统计方法，把可能影响机票价格差异的其他因素考虑在内。
We found that women paid on average $18 less per ticket than their male colleagues.
我们发现，女性每张机票平均比男同事少付18美元。
Further investigation allowed us to conclude that this gap is largely explained by the fact that women tended to book earlier than men, 1.8 days on average.
进一步调查后，我们得以断定，这一差距在很大程度上源于这样一个事实：女性订票往往比男性早，平均早1.8天。
We wanted to determine what was causing these gender differences in booking business trips, so we tested a variety of possible explanations, such as women choosing to plan ahead or male frequent travelers being inclined to book late.
我们想确定是什么造成了预订出差行程时的这些性别差异，于是检验了多种可能的解释，比如女性选择提前计划，或者经常出差的男性倾向于晚订票。
None of these explained away the gender gap, so we applied data collected from surveys that express consumer preferences that play a central role in economic decisions, such as patience and risk aversion.
以上解释都无法说明这一性别差距从何而来，于是我们运用了从调查中收集的数据，这些调查反映出在经济决策中起核心作用的消费者偏好，比如耐心和风险规避。
We found that only the concept of “negative reciprocity”—in which an employee who feels unfairly treated engages in negative behaviors, such as spending their company’s money less carefully—explains these differences.
我们发现，只有“消极互惠”这一概念能解释这些差异。这一概念指的是：觉得自己受到不公平对待的员工会做出消极行为，比如花公司的钱时不那么谨慎。
The surveys showed men tend to exhibit more of these negative behaviors than women.
这些调查显示，男性往往比女性更多地表现出这些消极行为。
This isn’t to say that all men engage in these behaviors—or that booking relatively late is a sign of abnormal behavior.
这并不是说所有男性都会做出这些行为，也不是说订票相对较晚就是异常行为的迹象。
It only means that the gender gap disappears when we plug in the negative reciprocity variable.
这只是意味着，代入消极互惠这一变量后，性别差距就消失了。
Prior research on negative reciprocity among workers found that it can result in lower employee motivation, business performance and workplace morale and culture.
以往关于员工中消极互惠现象的研究发现，消极互惠可能导致员工积极性降低、企业业绩下滑，以及职场士气低落、职场文化变差。
Our results show another way these negative behaviors can manifest themselves, as in airline bookings, and add to evidence that women are less likely to engage in them.
我们的研究结果表明，这些消极行为还可能以另一种方式表现出来，比如体现在机票预订上；这些结果也为“女性做出这类行为的可能性更小”这一观点增添了证据。
Companies spend significant sums of money on business travel.
公司在商务差旅上要花费相当可观的资金。
While that $18 difference per ticket may seem small, it adds up.
虽然每张机票18美元的差价也许看似不多，但积少成多。
Our analysis suggests early booking by women can translate into savings of $1 million a year for a large multinational company with 20,000 regular travelers.
我们的分析表明，对一家拥有20,000名常出差员工的大型跨国公司来说，女性提早订票每年可节省100万美元。